<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[hill repeats]]></title>
  <link href="http://hillrepeats.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://hillrepeats.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-03-06T10:01:12-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://hillrepeats.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Peter Kananen]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[playing the waiting game]]></title>
    <link href="http://hillrepeats.com/blog/2012/03/06/playing-the-waiting-game/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-06T07:56:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://hillrepeats.com/blog/2012/03/06/playing-the-waiting-game</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It has been over two weeks since I injured my heel and I stopped training. Thankfully, it&#8217;s getting better, but it&#8217;s not ready to run on yet. Although I suspected peroneal tendonitis at first, the presence of pain on both sides leads me to believe it could be achilles tendon bursitis. I did my hill repeats workout in Merrel Barefoot Trail Gloves, and I&#8217;m pretty sure that the steep downhill impact caused my problem. In any case, I continue to wait.</p>

<p>As soon as I found out I was injured, my motivation to eat well went out the window. I also stopped going to the <a href="http://www.rockquest.com">climbing gym</a> to do some climbing workouts that would keep me off of my ankle. Being injured really affected my attitude and desires, and 2 weeks in I don&#8217;t really seem to care much about my goal. That makes me sad. I just hope my motivation comes back when I&#8217;m well enough to run again.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[injured]]></title>
    <link href="http://hillrepeats.com/blog/2012/02/20/injured/"/>
    <updated>2012-02-20T21:30:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://hillrepeats.com/blog/2012/02/20/injured</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Well, just as I was starting to train for the Half Pig, I&#8217;ve had to stop because of an injury. As I mentioned, <a href="http://hillrepeats.com/blog/2012/02/15/calling-a-hill/">I took an extra rest day</a> because I felt like my body could use some rest. I had a tempo run on <a href="http://www.halhigdon.com/training/51133/Half-Marathon-Advanced-Training-Program/">the schedule</a> for Thursday, and I started out fairly well, but some mild pain on the outside of my left ankle progressed quickly, and by mile 3 I knew I needed to stop. It was hard to accept I couldn&#8217;t keep going, but  I knew the damage was done, so I made the &#8220;help, come pick me up&#8221; call to my wife and have spent the last few days trying to rest my foot and not think too much about it. It&#8217;s been tough.</p>

<p>Internet self-diagnosis seems to indicate peroneal tendonitis, but a visit to the chiropractor didn&#8217;t really confirm that. In any case, it seems to be a common injury for those adapting to minimalist shoes and doing too much, too soon. I suspect my hill repeats earlier in the week didn&#8217;t help much either. In any case, gotta wait for it to heal before I can do anything else.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[calling a hill]]></title>
    <link href="http://hillrepeats.com/blog/2012/02/15/calling-a-hill/"/>
    <updated>2012-02-15T21:14:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://hillrepeats.com/blog/2012/02/15/calling-a-hill</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Back in the late &#8217;90s when I ran cross country at Brighton High School, most of us boys were fairly undisciplined. When we&#8217;d run the trails away from the coach&#8217;s eye, it was common to hear someone call &#8220;hill&#8221;. Everyone was expected to walk the hill, and if an underclassman dared to run the hill in a bout of training bravado, he was typically cussed out by one of the underachieving seniors for violating the invoked hill rule.</p>

<p>On Monday I started <a href="http://www.halhigdon.com/training/51133/Half-Marathon-Advanced-Training-Program/">Hal Higdon&#8217;s Half Marathon Advanced Training Program</a>. It provides one day of rest a week. I&#8217;ve been trying to ramp up my mileage in the prior 4 weeks, knowing I don&#8217;t have a solid base to draw from. I&#8217;ve averaged about 22 the last two weeks, ending with a relatively fast <a href="http://runkeeper.com/user/pkananen/activity/70546044">8 mile run</a> on Sunday. My first official training day was an easy 3 miles, followed by our favorite, hill repeats, another easy 3 miles, and then a 40 minute tempo run. Still building my strength with minimalist shoes, the fast 8 mile run left me a little sore, and I decided today would be a rest day instead of an easy run. I could tell my body needed the rest. Sometimes you need to call &#8220;hill&#8221;, as long as it&#8217;s not because you don&#8217;t want to put in the work.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[I'm not a runner]]></title>
    <link href="http://hillrepeats.com/blog/2012/02/13/im-not-a-runner/"/>
    <updated>2012-02-13T14:30:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://hillrepeats.com/blog/2012/02/13/im-not-a-runner</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>That&#8217;s usually what I&#8217;ve told people whenever I&#8217;ve mentioned that I ran a 5K or had gone for a run in an attempt to stay in some level of fitness. It&#8217;s been 12 years since I regularly ran cross country in high school, and there have been years at a time where I haven&#8217;t ran almost at all. Sure, in the last 6 years I&#8217;ve done a few 5Ks in respectable times, and I&#8217;ve even run regularly for a few months at a time. But I&#8217;ve never considered myself a runner, and I probably wouldn&#8217;t even have used that description about myself when I was running 40 miles a week and 17 minute 5K races back in high school.</p>

<p>I never considered myself a runner because I&#8217;ve never really enjoyed running. But I&#8217;ve begun running again, and I&#8217;ve been enjoying it. A coworker of mine trained for a marathon in the fall, and his constant talk about his training plan kindled the thought of commiting to a race and seeing if I could perform well with a new challenge. I love having a plan and devoting myself to it, and I decided that in order to get back to the shape I&#8217;d like to be in and prove that I wasn&#8217;t past my prime, it was time to commit to a goal and see what happens. I&#8217;ve registered for the Flying Pig Half Marathon in Cincinnati, OH on May 6th, and I want to run it in 1:30. The next three months should be interesting.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
