<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: rest | hill repeats]]></title>
  <link href="http://hillrepeats.com/blog/categories/rest/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://hillrepeats.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-03-06T10:03:05-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://hillrepeats.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Peter Kananen]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[calling a hill]]></title>
    <link href="http://hillrepeats.com/blog/2012/02/15/calling-a-hill/"/>
    <updated>2012-02-15T21:14:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://hillrepeats.com/blog/2012/02/15/calling-a-hill</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Back in the late '90s when I ran cross country at Brighton High School, most of us boys were fairly undisciplined. When we'd run the trails away from the coach's eye, it was common to hear someone call "hill". Everyone was expected to walk the hill, and if an underclassman dared to run the hill in a bout of training bravado, he was typically cussed out by one of the underachieving seniors for violating the invoked hill rule.</p>

<p>On Monday I started <a href="http://www.halhigdon.com/training/51133/Half-Marathon-Advanced-Training-Program/">Hal Higdon's Half Marathon Advanced Training Program</a>. It provides one day of rest a week. I've been trying to ramp up my mileage in the prior 4 weeks, knowing I don't have a solid base to draw from. I've averaged about 22 the last two weeks, ending with a relatively fast <a href="http://runkeeper.com/user/pkananen/activity/70546044">8 mile run</a> on Sunday. My first official training day was an easy 3 miles, followed by our favorite, hill repeats, another easy 3 miles, and then a 40 minute tempo run. Still building my strength with minimalist shoes, the fast 8 mile run left me a little sore, and I decided today would be a rest day instead of an easy run. I could tell my body needed the rest. Sometimes you need to call "hill", as long as it's not because you don't want to put in the work.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
